# **Abhirup Sain**

**Nationality:** Indian **Date of birth:** 15/03/1997 **\Cong Phone number:** (+49) 17675471557

Email address: abhirupsain@gmail.com

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/abhirup-sain-57185254/

• Home: Hoyerswerdaer Str. 10, 01099 Dresden (Germany)

#### **ABOUT ME**

With over five years of experience in the Powertrain Domain at BOSCH, a performance-driven engineering specialist with a strong interest in electronics driven by a passion to comprehend circuits and logic, I am currently obtaining a Master's Degree in Nanoelectronic Systems at TU Dresden.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Senior Engineer**

**BOSCH India** [ 19/08/2019 - 11/09/2024 ]

City: BENGALURU | Country: India

- Successfully Integrated Requirements and Ensured AUTOSAR compliance for BMW MEDC17 and MDG1 projects using ASW and BSW components.
- Developed and optimized Functional Modules using MATLAB Simulink. Introduced Dynamic Link Library creation for Customer Testing.
- Extensive functional testing was successfully executed, resulting in an impressive 20% reduction in failure cases, through the proficient utilization of INCA and UDE, and the harnessing of capabilities provided by the dSPACE and LABCAR platforms.
- Led a high-performing team to conduct ASPICE spot checks at the Department level, resulting in consistently high-quality deliverables to OEM.
- Lead Automation Team and achieved 12% annual productivity.

## **Senior Engineer**

**BOSCH Austria** [ 31/07/2022 - 28/10/2022 ]

City: Wien | Country: Austria

- Successfully released the implementation of Software in Loop (SIL) build toolchains and automated the delivery process to OEM, leading to a 30% increase in productivity.
- Engineered and optimized a streamlined flow system to generate containers for Series Electronic Control Units, resulting in an impressive 50% reduction in manual intervention.
- Demonstrated exceptional technical prowess and problem-solving abilities, contributing to increased efficiency and productivity in the development process.

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

## **Master's In Nanoelectronic Systems**

**TU Dresden** [ 01/10/2024 – Current ]

City: Dresden | Country: Germany | Website: https://tu-dresden.de/

## **Bachelor of Technology**

Kalinga Institute of Industrial Technology [ 01/07/2015 - 01/04/2019 ]

City: Bhubaneswar | Country: India | Website: https://kiit.ac.in/ | Field(s) of study: Electronics and

Telecommunications Engineering | Final grade: 1.6

#### Intern

**PriceWaterHouseCoopers** [ 07/05/2018 – 29/06/2018 ]

City: Kolkata | Country: India | Website: https://www.pwc.in/

Created cutting-edge hybrid applications for Fortune 500 clients using IONIC Framework, incorporating Angular, HTML and CSS technologies.

#### Volunteer

**AIESEC** [ 25/05/2016 - 23/06/2016 ]

City: Johor Bahru | Country: Malaysia | Website: https://aiesec.org/

- AIESEC is an International Organization that provides young people with leadership development and cross-cultural global Internship opportunities.
- Responsible for website development using HTML, CSS for an NGO.

## **PROJECTS**

[ 01/08/2018 - 30/08/2018 ]

**Soldier Assistance System** The Soldier Assistance System is a comprehensive platform designed to provide support and assistance to soldiers in various operational environments.

- Developed a cutting-edge system for real-time location data exchange during emergencies, resulting in a 40% reduction in emergency.
- Utilized GSM module to enable seamless communication, facilitating rapid response and prioritizing safety protocols.

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

programming: Python, MATLAB and SQL / Unit Testing (xUnit) / Functional Programming Fundamentals / Git, Git Hub, SVN / CI&CD / Embedded C language / ECU flash tool / TPT (Time Partition Testing) / Universal Debug Engine (UDE) / ESYS, INCA

#### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Other language(s):

## **English**

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C2

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION** C2

**SPOKEN INTERACTION C2** 

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

#### **HOBBIES AND INTERESTS**

#### **Travelling**

**Photography**